export const chapter = "Chapter - 5: Tribal Societies in Colonial Rule ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the term used to refer to a member of a tribal society in the text?",
        optionA: "Indigenous",
        optionB: "Adivasi",
        optionC: "Nomad",
        correctAnswer: "B) Adivasi",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In a tribal society, where do most of their needs for food and livelihood come from?",
        optionA: "Urban areas",
        optionB: "Dense forests or hills",
        optionC: "Nearby towns or villages",
        correctAnswer: "B) Dense forests or hills",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of cultivation is commonly followed by many tribal societies?",
        optionA: "Terrace cultivation",
        optionB: "Jhum cultivation",
        optionC: "Organic cultivation",
        correctAnswer: "B) Jhum cultivation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the role of women in a tribal society, according to the text?",
        optionA: "Limited to domestic work",
        optionB: "Equal participation in both domestic and outside work",
        optionC: "Exclusively responsible for agricultural tasks",
        correctAnswer:
          "B) Equal participation in both domestic and outside work",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How do tribal societies typically communicate with the outside world when they need to meet their basic needs?",
        optionA: "By sending emissaries",
        optionB: "By learning the local language",
        optionC: "By using sign language",
        correctAnswer: "B) By learning the local language",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary source of livelihood for the Bakarwals of Kashmir?",
        optionA: "Fishing",
        optionB: "Goat rearing",
        optionC: "Crop cultivation",
        correctAnswer: "B) Goat rearing",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the purpose of a village committee in a tribal society?",
        optionA: "To organize religious ceremonies",
        optionB: "To enforce rules and settle disputes",
        optionC: "To elect a village chief",
        correctAnswer: "B) To enforce rules and settle disputes",
      },
      {
        question:
          "According to the text, what did the British introduce to bring the forests under their direct control?",
        optionA: "Forest laws",
        optionB: "Forest preservation methods",
        optionC: "Forest conservation initiatives",
        correctAnswer: "A) Forest laws",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What impact did the British rule have on tribal chiefs' authority and power?",
        optionA: "They retained their power and authority.",
        optionB: "They lost their power and authority.",
        optionC: "They became advisors to the British.",
        correctAnswer: "B) They lost their power and authority.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which region experienced a major tribal revolt in the 19th century, as mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Northeastern states",
        optionB: "Central India",
        optionC: "Chotanagpur region",
        correctAnswer: "C) Chotanagpur region",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "A tribal society is also known as an ________________.",
        optionA: "Indigenous",
        optionB: "Nomadic",
        optionC: "Adivasi",
        correctAnswer: "C) Adivasi",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Most tribal societies follow __________ cultivation, which involves clearing a patch of land, growing a crop for a couple of years, and then leaving it fallow.",
        optionA: "Traditional",
        optionB: "Terrace",
        optionC: "Jhum",
        correctAnswer: "C) Jhum",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Some tribal societies are traditional __________ who move with their herds of cattle, goats, sheep, etc., in search of grass.",
        optionA: "Farmers",
        optionB: "Fishermen",
        optionC: "Herders",
        correctAnswer: "C) Herders",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The members of a tribal society are arranged in a __________ group, where all members are equal, and there are no distinctions like that of caste.",
        optionA: "Heterogeneous",
        optionB: "Homogeneous",
        optionC: "Hierarchical",
        correctAnswer: "B) Homogeneous",
      },
      {
        question:
          "According to the text, many tribal societies visit nearby villages and towns for __________ where they engage in carrying loads, building sites, cultivating fields, etc.",
        optionA: "Shopping",
        optionB: "Daily wages",
        optionC: "Festivals",
        correctAnswer: "B) Daily wages",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced __________ laws to bring the forests under their direct control, restricting the tribals' free movement in the forest.",
        optionA: "Conservation",
        optionB: "Land settlement",
        optionC: "Forest",
        correctAnswer: "C) Forest",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal revolts occurred when the British sought to intrude into the way of life of the tribal people, leading to discontentment and __________.",
        optionA: "Collaboration",
        optionB: "Conversion",
        optionC: "Cooperation",
        correctAnswer: "B) Conversion",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Chotanagpur region experienced major tribal revolts when the British wanted to exploit the tribal land for the cultivation of cash crops and laying __________.",
        optionA: "Roads",
        optionB: "Railways",
        optionC: "Canals",
        correctAnswer: "B) Railways",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British interference in the tribal economy led to the disruption of traditional practices like jhum cultivation and the imposition of __________ on collecting forest produce.",
        optionA: "Taxes",
        optionB: "Restrictions",
        optionC: "Regulations",
        correctAnswer: "B) Restrictions",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal people protested and raised their voice against exploitation when their discontentment reached __________ limits.",
        optionA: "Tolerable",
        optionB: "Unbearable",
        optionC: "Manageable",
        correctAnswer: "B) Unbearable",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "A tribal society is a group of people with unique characteristics in language, social organization, and customs.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal societies prefer to live in densely populated urban areas.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Jhum cultivation is a common practice among many tribal societies.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Women in tribal societies usually have a limited role in both domestic and outside work.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Members of a tribal society are typically organized into a hierarchical social structure with distinct castes.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal societies rely on a strong sense of community and have a collective meeting place called Akhara.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced forest preservation methods to protect tribal lands and resources.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Conversion to Christianity was widely accepted by tribal people during British rule.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British rule led to an improvement in the tribal economy and the preservation of traditional practices.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal revolts occurred when the tribal people were content with British rule.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
